var questions = { 
    0: [{
            "question":"Which is the national water agency responsible for the collection, production, distribution and reclamation of water in Singapore?",
            "answers":["Agency for Science, Technology and Research (A*STAR)","Health Sciences Authority (HSA)","Public Utilities Board (PUB)","National Environmental Agency (NEA)"],
            "correct_index":2,
            "explanation":"The PUB was set up as a statutory on 1 May 1963 to coordinate the supply of electricity, piped gas, and water for Singapore. In 2001, PUB was reconstituted to become Singapore’s national water authority, overseeing the entire water loop."
        },
        {
            "question":"Which is the most expensive source of water in Singapore?",
            "answers":["Imported water","NEWater","Local Catchment water","Desalinated water"],
            "correct_index":3,
            "explanation":"Although desalination of water is expensive, it is still practised as it enables us to continuously produce high-quality water from both sea water and fresh water while maintaining healthy water levels in the reservoirs."
        },
        {
            "question":"How many reservoirs are there in Singapore in 2016?",
            "answers":["6 reservoirs","11 reservoirs","17 reservoirs","20 reservoirs"],
            "correct_index":2,
            "explanation":"The release of aquatic creatures into reservoirs is prohibited as it may affect the sustainability of ecology. Those caught doing so may be fined!"
        },
        {
            "question":"Which is Singapore’s oldest reservoir?",
            "answers":["Bedok Reservoir","MacRitchie Reservoir","Peirce Reservoir","Seletar Reservoir"],
            "correct_index":1,
            "explanation":"MacRitchie reservoir was built in 1867, made possible by a donation of S$13000 by philanthropist Tan Kim Seng."
        },
        {
            "question":"Where is Singapore's 1st NEWater plant located?",
            "answers":["Seletar","Punggol","Bedok","Chestnut Avenue"],
            "correct_index":2,
            "explanation":"Bedok NEWater Plant is Singapore’s first NEWater plant by Hyflux."
        },
        {
            "question":"Which is our Public Utilities Board (PUB)’s mascot?",
            "answers":["Water Willy","Water Whale","Water Wally","Water Warry"],
            "correct_index":2,
            "explanation":"Water Wally’s mission is to protect all water sources so that they can be clean, sparkling and free-flowing."
        },
        {
            "question":"What is NEWater?",
            "answers":["A new form of liquid which Singapore invented.","Clean water desalinated from the sea.","High-grade water purified from river water.","High-grade reclaimed water produced from treated used water."],
            "correct_index":3,
            "explanation":"By 2060, NEWater is expected to contribute 55 per cent of Singapore's water demand."
        },
        {
            "question":"How many ticks should you look out for when getting water efficiency labels products?",
            "answers":["1","2","3","4"],
            "correct_index":2,
            "explanation":"There are three types of Water Efficiency labels. Go find out the differences."
        }
    ],
    1: [{
            "question":"From which national tap is water ideal for wafer fabrication plants (which requires high-quality water) obtained?",
            "answers":["Water from local catchment","Imported water","NEWater","Desalinated water"],
            "correct_index":2,
            "explanation":"NEWater has passed more than 150,000 scientific tests and the water quality is well within World Health Organisation requirements!"
        },
        {
            "question":"When can Singapore become self-sufficient in its water supply?",
            "answers":["In 2011","In 2020","In 2061","Not possible in the foreseeable future."],
            "correct_index":2,
            "explanation":"By 2060, Singapore plans to triple its current NEWater capacity and increase by almost 10 times its desalination capacity."
        },
        {
            "question":"Where is Singapore’s largest NEWater factory located?",
            "answers":["Changi","Tuas","Kranji","Seletar"],
            "correct_index":0,
            "explanation":"Changi NEWater plant was officially opened in May 2010."
        },
        {
            "question":"Where are Singapore’s desalination plants located?",
            "answers":["Changi","Tuas","Seletar","Mandai"],
            "correct_index":1,
            "explanation":"SingSpring Desalination Plant is Singapore’s first desalination plant. Together with the second project, Tuaspring Desalination Plant, which was also built by Hyflux, the two desalination plants can meet up to 25% of the nation’s current water needs."
        },
        {
            "question":"When will Singapore’s water agreement with Malaysia expire?",
            "answers":["2024","2037","2061","2060"],
            "correct_index":2,
            "explanation":"Under the 99-year agreement which lasts until 2061, Singapore can draw water daily from the Johor River at the price of 3 sen per 1,000 gallons."
        },
        {
            "question":"How many litres of water does each Singaporean use daily in 2015?",
            "answers":["45 litres","85 litres","151 litres","195 litres"],
            "correct_index":2,
            "explanation":"That’s enough to fill almost two bathtubs!"
        },
        {
            "question":"In a typical household in Singapore, which activity takes up the largest amount of water usage?",
            "answers":["Flushing cistern","Kitchen sink","Shower","Laundry"],
            "correct_index":2,
            "explanation":"You would have used 45 litres of water for a 5-minute shower!"
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following programmes aims to develop people’s relationship with water and build in them a sense of shared ownership towards Singapore’s water resources?",
            "answers":["Save Water Campaigns programme","ABC Waters programme","Water Efficient Homes (WEH) programme","Water Efficient Buildings programme"],
            "correct_index":1,
            "explanation":"Kallang River @ Bishan-Ang Mo Kio Park is a flagship project under the ABC Waters programme. A combination of plants, natural materials such as rocks, and civil engineering techniques were introduced to soften the edges of the waterway, give it a natural appearance and prevent soil erosion."
        }
    ],
    2: [{
            "question":"Why is there a need for protected water catchments?",
            "answers":["It preserves the sensitive ecological balance in that area.","It prevents people from stealing water from the reservoir.","It prevents water in that area from drying out.","It acts as an emergency water source for Singapore."],
            "correct_index":0,
            "explanation":"Nutrients from different sources in the catchment (from pet waste, food waste, fertilisers, detergents and sediments, etc.) can have an impact on the ecosystem within the reservoir. When the conditions are favourable, such as warm water and sufficient sunlight, and when nutrients are available, algae may grow rapidly. This will affect the water quality."
        },
        {
            "question":"What percentage of Singapore’s land area will be used for water catchment in the future?",
            "answers":["60%","70%","80%","90%"],
            "correct_index":3,
            "explanation":"Most of it will be made up of unprotected catchments which are land where development is allowed, for example, for residential, commercial and non-pollutive industrial purposes."
        },
        {
            "question":"What was the duration of the water rationing, implemented in April 1963, when Singapore experienced a severe drought where water supply dropped to dangerously low levels?",
            "answers":["1 week","1 month","5 months","10 months"],
            "correct_index":3,
            "explanation":"\"During the water rationing periods, we couldn't bathe every day. Instead, we would take a white 'Good Morning' towel, soak it in water and use it to wipe ourselves.\"<br />-   Mr Leong, who was then 15 and a student<br />The New Paper, 6 Mar 2014"
        },
        {
            "question":"Which of the following stages is not part of the NEWater treatment process?",
            "answers":["Ultraviolet disinfection","Microfiltration","Distillation","Reverse Osmosis"],
            "correct_index":2,
            "explanation":"As of January 2017, there are five NEWater plants in Singapore, which can produce up to 40 per cent of Singapore's current demand of water."
        },
        {
            "question":"How much water can you save by using a cup when you brush your teeth?",
            "answers":["5 litres","11 litres","18 litres","29 litres"],
            "correct_index":1,
            "explanation":"Save 9 litres of water by showering one minute less!"
        },
        {
            "question":"What is the main advantage of desalination and NEWater?",
            "answers":["The methods are cost-friendly and effective.","The methods produce water of higher quality.","The methods are independent of fluctuations in rainfall.","The methods provide more water than the other methods."],
            "correct_index":2,
            "explanation":"Periods of drought can affect the reliability of Singapore's water supply, while sudden episodes of intense rainfall could overwhelm our drainage system and lead to flash floods."
        },
        {
            "question":"How much of the Earth’s water is suitable for drinking?",
            "answers":["1%","3%","30%","70%"],
            "correct_index":0,
            "explanation":"97% percent of the water on the earth is salt water, 2% is glacier ice at the North and South Poles."
        },
        {
            "question":"How many desalination plants does Singapore have in 2017?",
            "answers":["1","2","3","4"],
            "correct_index":2,
            "explanation":"The fourth desalination plant in Marina East will be built in 2019 whereas the fifth on Jurong Island is expected to be built around 2020."
        }
    ],
    3: [{
            "question":"Why was water conservation tax (WCT) introduced?",
            "answers":["Covers the costs incurred in the various stages of the water production process.","Reflects the cost of producing water from desalination and NEWater.","Encourages water conservation and to price water based on its scarcity value.","Operates and maintains the water network cost."],
            "correct_index":2,
            "explanation":"WCT is imposed as 30% of total water consumption to reinforce the message that water is precious from the very first drop."
        },
        {
            "question":"What is the maximum amount of water that Singapore can draw from Johor River in a day?",
            "answers":["50 million gallons","250 million gallons","400 million gallons","500 million gallons"],
            "correct_index":1,
            "explanation":"Imported water can supply up to 60 per cent of Singapore's water needs."
        },
        {
            "question":"By 2060, what proportion of Singapore’s water demands will be met by NEWater and Desalinated Water respectively?",
            "answers":["30%, 10%","40%, 20%","55%, 30%","60%, 40%"],
            "correct_index":2,
            "explanation":"By 2060, total water demand could almost double, with the non-domestic sector accounting for about 70%."
        },
        {
            "question":"How much water can the SingSpring Desalination Plant produce in a day?",
            "answers":["10 million gallons of water","20 million gallons of water","30 million gallons of water","50 million gallons of water"],
            "correct_index":2,
            "explanation":"The SingSpring and Tuaspring desalination plants can produce 100 million gallons of desalinated water a day."
        },
        {
            "question":"How many Olympic size swimming pools can Singapore’s daily water consumption of 430 million gallons fill?",
            "answers":["100 swimming pools","400 swimming pools","600 swimming pools","800 swimming pools"],
            "correct_index":3,
            "explanation":"Homes are consuming 45% and the non-domestic sector is taking up the rest."
        },
        {
            "question":"World Water Day is to raise awareness and call for stronger commitments to address the world’s water crisis. Which day is it celebrated?",
            "answers":["22 February","22 March","22 April","22 May"],
            "correct_index":1,
            "explanation":"The day focuses attention on the importance of fresh water and advocates for the sustainable management of freshwater resources."
        },
        {
            "question":"How many percent of the world’s water resources are needed for food production?",
            "answers":["20%","40%","50%","70%"],
            "correct_index":3,
            "explanation":"Producing food for the increasing world population will require 50% more freshwater."
        },
        {
            "question":"How many people in the world have no access to safe water supplies today?",
            "answers":["1 in 10","1 in 20","1 in 100","1 in 1000"],
            "correct_index":0,
            "explanation":"That is 783 million people!"
        }
    ]
};